Resume

Personal Details

Surname : Lieuwe
Name : Jansons
Residence : Groningen

Date of birth : 3 November 1977

Place of birth : Franeker
Nationality : Dutch
Drivers license : Yes

Personal website : www.jansons.nl/english/

LinkedIn : http://www.linkedin.com/in/lieuwejansons



Profile

Lieuwe is an all-round IT consultant who has seen the dynamics surrounding IT solutions from all sides of the table. After finishing his bachelor in Management, Economics and Law he discovered he was above average in learning computer languages and coming up with and building solutions in software regarding his working processes.

In the past eight years, he has had the following roles regarding designing and building software solutions:

- (WBSO) advisor;
- Teamleader;
- Functional designer;
- Technical designer;
- Consultant for clients;
- Software engineer;
- Freelance contractor;
- Client.

By gaining experience in all these roles, he is ideally someone who can translate the costumers needs into IT solutions regarding the complete process during the build of software.

Lieuwe is a dedicated professional. He can be deployed as a consultant, functional designer, and project manager. Lieuwe is very involved in project on which he gets deployed. He prefers to take part in a project from the analysis of the issues to the implementation of the (IT)solution.

Both on the analytical level and the communicative level, Lieuwe is very strong. Through is analytical skills he is ideally suited for complex tasks. Formulating strategies and advising clients whilst managing great client relations can be safely entrusted to him.

Lieuwe is a people's person. He knows how to quickly adapt to the language of non IT clients and users, which bridges the gap between business and IT. He is highly appreciated by users and project colleagues.

Lieuwe thinks face-to-face contact with all involved in a project is of great importance. Therefore, he is very willing to travel to clients. He has a positive, solution-oriented attitude, is enthusiastic, creative person with a good sense of humor.

Education

2008 Prince2 Foundation (certificate)

1997 - 2002 Bachelor Management, Economics and Law (degree) 1995 – 1997 Senior Vocational Education – Economics (degree)

1997 Total Communication (Sign language)

Specifieke kennisgebieden

Excellent knowledge of the standards of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3).

<u>Programming languages</u> <u>Experience</u>

XHTML, HTML, CSS 5 years; excellent knowledge of the standards of the World Wide

Web Consortium (W3 (<u>www.w3.org/</u>)) and the guidelines regarding accessibility (WAI 1.0 en 2.0 (<u>www.w3.org/wai</u>))

JavaScript 5 years; excellent knowledge PHP, MySQL 5 years; excellent knowledge

Visual Basic for Applications 3 years; fluent

SQL 7 years; excellent knowledge

<u>Databases</u> <u>Experience</u> Oracle 2 years, fluent

MsAccess 5 jaar; excellent knowledge Niku Workbench 1 jaar; very good knowledge

Other software Ervaring

Astah 6 months, reasonable knowledge

Niku Time 1 year; very fluent
Macro Scheduler 2 years; fluent
Photoshop 5 years; very fluent

Werkervaring

2011 Agency of the Ministry of Economic Affairs in Zwolle

Interim Subsidy Advisor WBSO

Tasks:

- Assessing grant applications for the a fiscal stimulation package on R&D work;
- Gathering detailed information regarding grant applications;
- Communicating (negative and positive) judgments on grant applications to applicants.

2010

StormMC in Groningen Projectmanager, Functional Designer

Tasks:

- Supervising a team of experts who deal with building websites, banners and landing pages;
- Communicating with clients regarding functional specifications, designs and progress;
- Creation of an administration for planning;
- Creation of a financial administration;
- Reversing the existing working method to a standard working method for building websites;
- Adding a "Business Case" to the existing working method
- Adding "Functional design", "Usage of click models" and "Testing" to the existing working method
- Writing a standard for a Business Case for websites;
- Writing a standard for a Functional Design (with click models) for websites;
- Making a standard test report for testing websites;
- Coaching the sales department regarding the costs of and terms and conditions regarding websites;
- Writing functional designs with click models;

2007 - 2010

Ordina in Groningen

Teamleader, Functioneel Designer, Software Engineer Tasks:

 Functional and technisch designs and teamlead during the rebuild of an online HRM application which is used by clients, including KLM-Air France, Achmea (large Dutch insurance company, Albert Heyn (large dutch retailer) and Nike.

Technology used: Oracle Portal Computer languages used: PL/SQL, XML, HTML, JavaScript, CSS Project method: Agile

- Determining Function Points of an online HRM application Technology used: Oracle Portal Computer languages used: PL/SQL, XML, HTML, JavaScript, CSS
- Designs for expantion of an online HRM application Technology used: Oracle Portal Computer languages used: PL/SQL, XML, HTML, JavaScript, CSS
- Ministry of Justice: designing interfaces between Oracle eBS and custom-made applications in use at the Ministry of Justice
- Technology used: Oracle eBS, several custom-made application in use at the Ministry of Justice;
 Computer languages used: PL/SQL, XML Project method: Waterfall
- Teamlead and software engineering during the build of an HRM for internal use at Ordina:

Technology used: ADF Faces

Computer languages used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java Project method: Rational Unified Process (RUP)

2006 - 2007

Traffic4U in Groningen Organic Search Consultant

Tasks:

- Giving advice to the large clients (large webshops like Wehkamp, energy companies like Essent, insurance companies like CZ) regarding the search engine friendliness of their website
- · Rewriting source code of websites of clients
- Writing a document which compares guidelines regarding accessibility and functional and technical aspects regarding Search Engine Optimalisation (SEO).

Other working experience

2005 - 2006

Nijestee in Groningen

Communications Employee

Tasks:

- Giving advice during the design of a new website;
- Content management of websites
- Giving advice regarding the internal spread of company information

2004 - 2006

Freelancer in Groningen

Tasks:

- · Building and maintaining websites
- · Designing illustrations and flyers
- Doing administrative tasks at theater productions

2003 - 2005

KPN in Groningen Backoffice Employee

Tasks:

- Data entry
- Speeding up working processes (average speed gain: 300%):
 - Rewriting working processes
 - Building interfaces for administrative application regarding activating new mobile numbers, changing SIMnumbers, changing and activating client accounts, migration of pre-paid to postpaid subscriptions
- Coaching colleagues in the usage of the new (self written) software

2001 - 2003

Municipality of Groningen in Groningen **Planner**

Tasks:

- Keeping the administration regarding the planning up to date
- Synchronizing the administration regarding the planning and the financial administration
- Speeding up working processes (average reduction of time of administrative tasks from 3,5 days to 3 hours).
- Coaching colleagues in the usage of the new (self written) software
- Writing software applications in MsAccess regarding several administrative tasks of the department:
 - Registrary of building applications
 - Interfaces between financial administration and the planning software

Traineeship

- Investigation on the application of a hallmark for newly built houses
- Designing and building an registrar system in MsAccess for documents of the department

1998 - 2000

RDR in Groningen

Caretaker

Tasks:

- Managing supplies of office supply inentory
- Fixing several small technical malfunctions
- Parceldistribution throughout the organisation
- · Providing and maintaining meeting rooms

External activities

2008 - 2009

Freelancer on online volunteeringplatform www.nabuur.com

Tasks:

- Giving advice on IT sollutions
- · Giving advice in managing projects
- Making a course in van cursus cost calculations
- Designing graphical van graphics (flyers, brochures, logos)

1995 - 1997

Volunteer at Frido Foundation Tasks:

- Organizing activities for young people with hearing disabilities
- Managing the finances of the youth wing of the foundation

Languages

	Reading	Speaking	Writing
Dutch	Motherlanguage	Motherlanguage	Motherlanguage
Duits	Reasonable	Reasonable	Hardly able
Engels	Good	Good	Good
Groninger gebarentaal	Good	Good	Not applicable

Hobbies

Building computerprograms (like websites), painting, drawing, achitecture, music, history